Are you ready, kids?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
(children)
Aye, aye, Captain!
（儿童）
是啊是啊，队长！
I can't hear you.
我听不到你说话。
(children)
Aye, aye, Captain!
（儿童）
是啊是啊，队长！
Oh...
哦...
Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea?
谁住在菠萝里
在海底？
(children)
SpongeBob SquarePants!
（儿童）
海绵宝宝！
Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he
吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的
(children)
SpongeBob SquarePants!
（儿童）
海绵宝宝！
If nautical nonsense
be something you wish
如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西
(children)
SpongeBob SquarePants!
（儿童）
海绵宝宝！
Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish
然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通
- SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
- 海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
(all)
SpongeBob SquarePants!
（全部）
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
SpongeBob
海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
[piccolo melody]
[短笛旋律]
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[upbeat ukulele music]
[欢快的尤克里里音乐]
*
[rooster crows]
[公鸡打鸣]
[Squidward hums]
[章鱼哥哼哼]
Aah.
啊。
Wow, 20 minutes in the bath
is probably enough.
哇，洗澡20分钟
可能就足够了。
Aah, another day...
啊啊，改天了……
Another day.
又一天。
[snoring]
[打鼾]
[fog horn]
[雾号]
(SpongeBob)
Whoa! Oh, doh, ow, oh, ow, aah!
（海绵宝宝）
哇！噢，噢，噢，噢，噢，啊！
[shower runs]
[淋浴运行]
Ow, whoa, oof, ow!
噢，哇，噢，噢！
Ready for work.
准备工作了。
Oh, morning, Squidward! I--
哦，早上好，章鱼哥！我 -
Oh! Not ready for work!
哦！还没准备好上班！
Doh, oof, ow, ow, ooh!
噢，噢，噢，噢，噢！
Whatever.
任何。
- Thanks for waiting, Squidward.
- I wasn't waiting.
- 谢谢你的等待，章鱼哥。
- 我没等。
[laughs] I was in such a hurry
I almost forgot my pants.
[笑]我太着急了
我差点忘记穿裤子了。
- Yes, I saw that.
- I guess I was in a panic.
- 是的，我看到了。
- 我想我当时很恐慌。
I mean, I can't believe we're
running so late for work,
我的意思是，我不敢相信我们
上班这么晚了
can you? Huh, Squidward?
Can you believe it?
你可以吗？哈，章鱼哥？
你能相信吗？
Are you panicking too?
你也惊慌失措吗？
Late for work, late for work,
we're running late for work,
上班迟到，上班迟到，
我们上班要迟到了
right?
正确的？
Right. We're going to be there
15 minutes early.
正确的。我们会去那里
提前15分钟。
I know! Only 15 minutes early?
我知道！只提前15分钟？
Maybe we should take a shortcut.
也许我们应该走捷径。
[gasps]
Squidward, what are you doing?
[喘气]
章鱼哥，你在做什么？
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- Ugh...
- SpongeBob, look.
- 呃...
- 海绵宝宝，看。
(Squidward)
We're walking
in a straight line.
（章鱼哥）
我们走着
在一条直线上。
I don't follow.
我不跟。
A straight line is the shortest
distance between any two points.
直线是最短的
任意两点之间的距离。
Speak English, brainiac.
[laughs]
说英语，脑残。
[笑]
Well, see, you have point A,
where you start,
好吧，看，你有A点，
从哪里开始，
and then there's point,
uh, point, uh...
然后还有一点，
呃，重点，呃……
I don't even know
what I'm talking about.
我什至不知道
我在说什么。
Mmm, strawberry.
嗯，草莓。
Tick!
打钩！
Oh no! Now we're only going to
be 14 minutes early for work.
哦不！现在我们只需要
提前 14 分钟上班。
Oh, there's got to be a shortcut
around here somewhere.
哦，总得有个捷径吧
就在这附近的某个地方。
Oh, for the last time.
Straight line, point A.
哦，最后一次。
直线，A点。
There's no shortcut.
没有捷径。
There is always a shortcut.
总有捷径。
What moron told you that?
哪个白痴告诉你的？
There's always a shortcut.
总有一条捷径。
Ah.
啊。
Squidward, I am going to find
that shortcut.
章鱼哥，我要找到
那个捷径。
Look, the Krusty Krab is right
at the end of the block.
看，蟹堡王说得对
在块的末尾。
Yoo hoo!
哟吼！
[gasps] You're not going
to come with me?
[喘气]你不会去
跟我一起去吗？
No, SpongeBob. I'm just going
to struggle through
不，海绵宝宝。我正要去
去奋斗
the rest of this walk alone.
剩下的路就一个人走。
Well, I guess this is
where we part ways.
嗯，我想这就是
我们分道扬镳的地方。
But I can't wait to see
your face when you get to work
但我已经等不及要看
当你上班时你的脸
and I'm already there.
我已经在那里了。
[laughs] That's the face!
That's the look!
[笑]这就是脸！
就是这个样子！
[SpongeBob laughs]
[海绵宝宝笑]
* First you do a zig,
then you take a little zag. *
* 首先你做一个之字形，
然后你稍微弯曲一下。 *
* That's how you find
a shortcut. *
* 这就是你找到的方式
一条捷径。 *
* Crawl underneath a fence,
struggle through a bush, *
*爬到栅栏下面，
挣扎着穿过灌木丛，*
* and that's how you find
a shortcut. *
* 这就是你找到的方式
一条捷径。 *
- Huh?
- Straight line.
- 啊？
- 直线。
Point A to point B.
You're still not getting it.
A点到B点。
你还是没明白。
Oh, tartar sauce. Maybe I should
have zagged when I zigged.
哦，塔塔酱。也许我应该
当我曲折时，已经曲折了。
*First you do a zag,
crawl underneath a fence *
*首先你做一个曲折，
爬到栅栏下面*
* Then you take a little zig,
that's how you find a shortcut *
* 然后你稍微弯曲一下，
这就是你找到捷径的方法*
[laughs]
There, that's better.
[笑]
在那里，这样更好。
[wolf howls]
[狼嚎]
Oh. [nervous laugh]
哦。 [紧张的笑声]
Now this is what I call
a real great shortcut.
现在这就是我所说的
一个真正伟大的捷径。
Now all I have to do is remember
my wilderness training
现在我要做的就是记住
我的荒野训练
so I don't get lost.
所以我不会迷路。
The first rule of wilderness
training is map out your course
荒野第一法则
培训是规划你的课程
by taking note
of local landmarks.
通过记下
当地地标。
Local landmarks.
Ah-hah!
啊哈！
Right at this large,
unusual shell.
就这么大，
不寻常的外壳。
Right at this abandoned sofa.
就在这个废弃的沙发旁边。
And jog left
at the broken fire hydrant.
然后向左慢跑
在破损的消防栓处。
[laughs]
[笑]
There it is. The Krusty Krab.
就在那里。蟹堡王。
Ooh!
[panting]
哦！
[气喘吁吁]
[crash]
[碰撞]
[slow Hawaiian-style music]
【缓慢的夏威夷风格音乐】
*
Aah.
啊。
Well, look at this.
Lazin' about.
好吧，看看这个。
偷懒了。
Can I get you anything else?
Another pillow maybe?
我还能给你找点别的吗？
也许另一个枕头？
A cappuccino machine?
卡布奇诺咖啡机？
No, thanks, I got one.
不，谢谢，我有一个。
[whistles]
[口哨声]
Perfect. No customers,
no SpongeBob.
完美的。没有顾客，
没有海绵宝宝。
Oh, for kelp's sake.
You're a lost cause.
哦，为了海带。
你是一个失败的事业。
[choir sings]
[合唱团唱歌]
[gasps] The Krabby Krust?
[喘气]蟹堡？
Is that the name
of a restaurant?
是这个名字吗
一家餐馆的？
No, it's a typo.
不，这是一个错字。
Could you perhaps tell me
你能告诉我吗
how to get to
the Krusty Krab from here?
怎么去
蟹堡王是这里的吗？
- Never heard of it.
- Oh, you should try it.
- 从来没有听说过。
- 哦，你应该尝试一下。
It's the best place to eat
in all of Bikini Bottom.
这是最好的吃饭的地方
在所有比基尼底部。
Here, take these coupons.
来，拿走这些优惠券。
Thanks. I'm going to
go there right now.
谢谢。我要去
现在就去那里。
I thought you didn't know
where the Krusty Krab was.
我以为你不知道
蟹堡王所在的地方。
Oh, what do I do now?
哦，我现在该怎么办？
[sobs]
[抽泣]
Remember your landmarks.
记住你的地标。
Sandy's wilderness tips
are always on the money.
桑迪的荒野小贴士
总是靠钱。
Okay, let's see. I came from...
好吧，让我们看看。我来自...
No, I came...
不，我来了……
I'm lost!
我迷路了！
[screams]
[尖叫声]
Hey, there's one
of my landmarks.
嘿，有一个
我的地标。
The broken fire hydrant.
Hello, hydrant.
破损的消防栓。
你好，消火栓。
I'm going to call you Heidi.
Heidi the hydrant.
我要叫你海蒂。
海蒂消防栓。
So many broken fire hydrants.
What do I do now, Heidi?
这么多破损的消防栓。
我现在该怎么办，海蒂？
If only I could telephone
Squidward, he'd help me out.
如果我能打电话就好了
章鱼哥，他会帮我的。
Hey, that thing looks
kind of like a phone.
嘿，那东西看起来
有点像电话。
Wow, this is weird.
哇，这很奇怪。
It's like a phone,
but you put money in it.
就像电话一样，
但你把钱放进去。
[change jingles]
[更改歌曲]
My last dime.
我的最后一毛钱。
I hope this works.
我希望这能起作用。
[phone rings]
[电话铃声]
Krusty Krab,
may I reluctantly help you?
蟹堡王,
我可以勉强帮你吗？
It's me, Squidward. SpongeBob.
I'm calling from a payphone.
是我，章鱼哥。海绵宝宝。
我用公用电话打电话。
You don't say.
How's that shortcut of yours?
你不说。
你的那个捷径怎么样？
Not good. I think I made a wrong
turn at the abandoned sofa.
不好。我想我做错了
转身看向废弃的沙发。
All there is around here
are broken fire hydrants.
一切都在这附近
是损坏的消防栓。
What should I do?
我应该怎么办？
(phone operator)
If you'd like to continue
this call,
（电话接线员）
如果您想继续
这个电话，
- please insert another dime.
- I don't have a dime.
- 请再插入一毛钱。
- 我一毛钱都没有。
Operator, please, please,
can you tell me where I am?
接线员，请，请，
你能告诉我我在哪里吗？
(operator)
If you'd like to know where you
are, please insert another dime.
（操作员）
如果你想知道你在哪里
是，请再插入一毛钱。
Hold on!
坚持，稍等！
[cell phone rings]
[手机响]
Two nickels? I need a dime.
两镍币？我需要一毛钱。
Oh, I'm never going
to get to work.
哦，我永远不会去
去上班。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Looking for a dime
in this abandoned sofa.
寻找一毛钱
在这个废弃的沙发里。
This is our abandoned sofa, pal.
这是我们废弃的沙发，朋友。
Whatcha doin' there,
drinking soda?
在那里做什么，
喝苏打水？
What's it to ya?
关你什么事？
Isn't a little early
to be hitting
是不是有点早了
被击中
the high-fructose corn syrup?
高果糖玉米糖浆？
Hey, listen.
嘿，听着。
I know this gigantic soda
isn't good for me,
我知道这个巨大的苏打水
对我来说不好
but sometimes it gives me
the kick I need
但有时它给了我
我需要的踢
to start my busy day
as a pedicab driver.
开始我忙碌的一天
作为三轮车司机。
Ooh, you drive a pedicab?
哦，你开三轮车吗？
Yes, sir!
是的，先生！
You need a ride somewhere?
您需要搭车去某个地方吗？
Yes! To the Krusty Krab
and step on it!
是的！致蟹堡王
并踩在它上面！
Way to go, Scott!
干得好，斯科特！
Yeah, he's almost saved enough
是的，他已经攒够了
to attend
a community college next year.
参加
明年是社区大学。
Thanks a lot, Scott.
Stay in school.
非常感谢，斯科特。
留在学校。
Krusty Klam? [gasps]
库斯蒂克拉姆？ [喘气]
Wait, Scott. Come back!
等等，斯科特。回来！
[gasps] Tartar sauce!
[喘气]塔塔酱！
- Tock!
- No!
- 托克！
- 不！
Over the cliff.
越过悬崖。
Through the toxic runoff.
通过有毒径流。
Make a right at the
disease-filled sewer pipe.
在
充满疾病的下水道。
Face-first into this fetid muck.
脸朝下进入这片恶臭的淤泥。
Over the garbage pile.
越过垃圾堆。
Fall down this mountain
of broken glass.
掉下这座山
碎玻璃。
Over the excruciatingly sharp
razor wire.
越过极其尖锐的
刀片刺网。
[sputtering]
[溅射]
Up this massive hill.
爬上这座巨大的山丘。
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
That's the Krusty Krab.
这就是蟹堡王。
And I'm still two minutes early.
而且我还早了两分钟。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
I made it. Oh, I made it.
我做到了。哦，我做到了。
Oh, random Krusty Krab patrons,
how I've missed you.
噢，蟹堡王的随机顾客，
我多么想念你啊。
Oh, how I've missed
your youthful faces.
哦，我多么怀念
你年轻的脸庞。
I missed the bathroom, too.
[toilet flushing]
我也想念洗手间。
[冲厕所]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
But most of all,
I missed you, choking guy.
但最重要的是，
我想念你，窒息的家伙。
Patrick? How did you get here?
帕特里克？你是怎么到这里来的？
Same way I always do.
我总是这样做。
Scott gave me a ride
in his pedicab.
斯科特载我一程
在他的三轮车里。
[bicycle horn squeaks]
[自行车喇叭吱吱作响]
Squidward! Squidward,
can you believe I made it?
章鱼哥！章鱼哥，
你能相信我做到了吗？
Oh.
哦。
- Congratulations.
- What are you doing, boy?
- 恭喜。
- 你在做什么，男孩？
You're scaring away all me
customers with your foul stench.
你吓跑了我所有人
顾客带着你的恶臭。
Mr. Krabs!
蟹老板！
Oh, no, lad. You're not coming
in here looking like that.
哦，不，小伙子。你不来了
在这里看起来像那样。
[fog horn]
[雾号]
You're going straight home
for a nice, long bubble bath.
你直接回家
享受一个美好的、长时间的泡泡浴。
Aye, aye, sir.
是啊，是啊，先生。
What? He gets to go home
and take a bubble bath?
什么？他要回家了
并洗个泡泡浴？
That's my thing.
那是我的事。
Yes, it is.
是的。
And consequently, you are
just neat as a pin.
因此，你是
就像别针一样整齐。
Now get to work!
现在开始工作吧！
I'm as neat as a pin.
我干净得像针一样。
I'll show you neat as a pin.
我会告诉你整洁如针。
[jabbering]
[叽叽喳喳]
Where's my bubble bath,
Mr. Krabs?
我的泡泡浴在哪里
蟹老板？
There you go.
就这样吧。
Now get to work.
现在开始工作吧。
Are you guys open?
I have coupons.
你们还开放吗？
我有优惠券。
Buy one, get one free.
买一送一。
Oh, no.
It says, "Buy one for a fee."
哦，不。
它说：“付费购买一个。”
Oh. I stand corrected.
哦。我纠正了。